Guide to the Livingston Farrand papers, 1921-1939.
Farrand, Livingston Papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Livingston Farrand papers, 1921-1939.
3/5/7
Livingston, Farrand, 1867-1939.
40.7 cubic ft.
Correspondence, office files, reports, letters of transmittal, notices of appointment to committees, scrapbooks, cross reference sheets, clippings, diplomas, photographs, and certificates.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Livingston Farrand Papers consist of correspondence, office files, reports, letters of transmittal, notices of appointment to committees, scrapbooks, cross reference sheets, clippings, diplomas, and certificates deriving from his presidency of Cornell University from 1921 to 1937. The collection consists chiefly of correspondence, pertaining largely to the routine administration of the President's Office and the University. Subjects include student and faculty issues, student health, athletics, Cornell United Religious Work including arrangements for Sage Chapel preachers, alumni affairs, fraternities, the Cornell-in-China Program, and the University Faculty; also, relations with and the administration of the Law School, the College of Arts and Sciences, the Cornell University Medical College, the College of Engineering, Cornell University Library, the Office of the Comptroller, ROTC, the New York State College of Agriculture, and the New York State Veterinary College, and relations with New York Hospital, the city of Ithaca (N.Y.), the United States Office of Education, the New York State Department of Education, the American Council on Education, the Carnegie Corporation and Carnegie Foundation, the Heckscher Research Council, and the United States War Department. Included is a portfolio of photographs by Lewis W. Hine, created for the American Red Cross during a survey mission from 1918-1919.
Other topics include instances of student malfeasance and scholastic failure, racial discrimination and anti-semitism on campus, concern with communist influence in the educational community, and Farrand's personal interests in eugenics and public health. Major correspondents include Arthur Allen, Howard E. Babcock, Carl Becker, Romeyn Berry, Cornelius Betten, Charles Bostwick, Charles K. Burdick, Foster M. Coffin, L. M. Dennis, R. Louise Fitch, Harold Flack, Frank E. Gannett, William A. Hammond, Frank H. Hiscock, Carl E. Ladd, Albert R. Mann, Archie Palmer, George Rogalsky, Flora Rose, Robert Treman, Allan H. Treman, Myron C. Taylor, Martha van Rensselaer, George F. Warren, and J. DuPratt White.
Also included is a bound typewritten report on the state of Cornell University and its current financial needs as of 1924.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Livingston Farrand was born in 1867 in Newark, New Jersey. He graduated from Princeton University in 1888, and took an M.D. degree from the College of Physicians and Surgeons in New York. He was an instructor in psychology at Columbia University, and later adjunct professor. Interested in primitive psychology, he joined expeditions to the Pacific northwest with Franz Boas and others, and was appointed professor of anthropology at Columbia in 1903. Farrand was deeply concerned with public health questions, serving as Executive Secretary of the National Association for the Study and Prevention of Tuberculosis from 1905 to 1914. In 1914 he became President of the University of Colorado. In 1917, as director of the Anti-Tuberculosis Commission, he worked in France under the auspices of the International Health Division of the Rockefeller Foundation. His success led to his appointment after the war as chairman of the Central Committee of the American Red Cross. In 1921 he was inaugurated as the fourth president of Cornell University, a position he held until 1937. He died in 1939.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Livingston Farrand Papers consist of correspondence, office files, reports, letters of transmittal, notices of appointment to committees, scrapbooks, cross reference sheets, clippings, diplomas, and certificates deriving from his presidency of Cornell University from 1921 to 1937. The collection consists chiefly of correspondence, pertaining largely to the routine administration of the President's Office and the University. Subjects include student and faculty issues, student health, athletics, Cornell United Religious Work including arrangements for Sage Chapel preachers, alumni affairs, fraternities, the Cornell-in-China Program, and the University Faculty; also, relations with and the administration of the Law School, the College of Arts and Sciences, the Cornell University Medical College, the College of Engineering, Cornell University Library, the Office of the Comptroller, ROTC, the New York State College of Agriculture, and the New York State Veterinary College, and relations with New York Hospital, the city of Ithaca (N.Y.), the United States Office of Education, the New York State Department of Education, the American Council on Education, the Carnegie Corporation and Carnegie Foundation, the Heckscher Research Council, and the United States War Department. Included is a portfolio of photographs by Lewis W. Hine, created for the American Red Cross during a survey mission from 1918-1919.
Other topics include instances of student malfeasance and scholastic failure, racial discrimination and anti-semitism on campus, concern with communist influence in the educational community, and Farrand's personal interests in eugenics and public health. Major correspondents include Arthur Allen, Howard E. Babcock, Carl Becker, Romeyn Berry, Cornelius Betten, Charles Bostwick, Charles K. Burdick, Foster M. Coffin, L. M. Dennis, R. Louise Fitch, Harold Flack, Frank E. Gannett, William A. Hammond, Frank H. Hiscock, Carl E. Ladd, Albert R. Mann, Archie Palmer, George Rogalsky, Flora Rose, Robert Treman, Allan H. Treman, Myron C. Taylor, Martha van Rensselaer, George F. Warren, and J. DuPratt White.
Also included is a bound typewritten report on the state of Cornell University and its current financial needs as of 1924.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Farrand, Livingston, 1867-1939.; Allen, Arthur A. (Arthur Augustus), 1885-1964.; Babcock, H. E. (Howard Edward), 1889-1950.; Becker, Carl L. (Carl Lotus), 1873-1945.; Berry, Romeyn, 1881-1957.; Betten, Cornelius, 1877-1962.; Bostwick, Charles Dibble, 1870-1937.; Burdick, Charles K. (Charles Kellogg), 1883-1940.; Coffin, Foster M.; Dennis, L. M.; Fitch, Louise.; Flack, Harold.; Gannett, Frank E. (Frank Ernest), 1876-1957.; Hammond, William A.; Hine, Lewis Wickes, 1874-1940; Hiscock, Frank H.; Ladd, Carl E., 1888-1943.; Mann, Albert Russell, 1880-1947.; Palmer, Archie M.; Rogalsky, George.; Rose, Flora, 1874-; Treman, Allan H., 1899-1975.; Taylor, Myron Charles, 1874-1959.; Van Rensselaer, Martha, 1864-1932.; White, J. DuPratt, 1869-1939.; Allen, Arthur A. (Arthur Augustus), 1885-1964; Babcock, H. E. (Howard Edward), 1889-1950; Becker, Carl L. (Carl Lotus), 1873-1945; Berry, Romeyn, 1881-1957; Betten, Cornelius, 1877-1962; Bostwick, Charles Dibble, 1870-1937; Burdick, Charles K. (Charles Kellogg), 1883-1940; Coffin, Foster M.; Dennis, L. M.; Fitch, Louise; Flack, Harold; Gannett, Frank E. (Frank Ernest), 1876-1957; Hammond, William A.; Hiscock, Frank H.; Ladd, Carl E., 1888-1943; Mann, Albert Russell, 1880-1947; Palmer, Archie M.; Rogalsky, George; Rose, Flora, 1874-; Taylor, Myron Charles, 1874-1959; Treman, Allan H., 1899-1975; Van Rensselaer, Martha, 1864-1932; White, J. DuPratt, 1869-1939; Cornell University.; Cornell University -- Administration.; Cornell University -- Students.; Cornell University -- Faculty.; Cornell University -- Presidents.; Cornell University -- Alumni and alumnae.; Cornell University -- Libraries.; Cornell University -- Office of the President.; Cornell University. University Faculty.; Cornell University. Cornell University Library.; Cornell University. Board of Trustees.; Cornell University -- Athletics.; Cornell University Medical College.; Sage Chapel (Cornell University).; Cornell University. College of Engineering.; Cornell University. College of Arts and Sciences.; Cornell University. Office of the Comptroller.; New York State College of Agriculture.; New York State College of Home Economics.; New York State Veterinary College.; United States. Reserve Officers' Training Corps.; New York (State). Department of Education.; United States. Office of Education.; American Council on Education.; Carnegie Corporation of New York.; Carnegie Foundation.; Heckscher Research Council.; American Red Cross.; United States. War Department.; American Council on Education; Carnegie Corporation of New York; Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching; Cornell University; Cornell University. Board of Trustees; Cornell University. College of Arts and Sciences; Cornell University. College of Engineering; Cornell University. Medical College; New York State College of Agriculture; New York State College of Home Economics; New York State Veterinary College; Sage Chapel (Cornell University); United States. Reserve Officers' Training Corps; United States. Office of Education; United States. War Department
Subjects:
Race discrimination.; Antisemitism.; Eugenics.; Public health.; Education.; Athletics.; College students -- Conduct of life.; College administrators.; College presidents.; Antisemitism; Athletics; College administrators; College presidents; College students -- Conduct of life; Education; Eugenics; Libraries; Management; Presidents; Public health; Race discrimination; Students; Universities and colleges -- Alumni and alumnae; Universities and colleges -- Faculty
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Includes collection #3-5-1353.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
The Livingston Farrand papers consist of a single alphabetical arrangement. University offices, departments, and administrative divisions are filed by the name of the incumbent. The folder headings are arranged according to natural alphabetical prefixes, ie. A-ACE, R-ROW, etc, or according to subject heading, ie. American Council, or subject heading and alphabetical prefix, ie. Cornell University Medical College CA-F.
The Index contains only selected subjects and correspondents.
CONTAINER LIST
- A-AC Miscellaneous., 1924-37 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Abel, Theodore F.; Abt, Henry Edward; MacCracken, Henry Noble. Abraham Lincoln University; Academic freedom; Ives Act; Communism.
- AC-AD Miscellaneous., 1922-25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Acheson, Glen; Dobie, Gilmour; Acosta, Ignacio Bird; Adams, Bristow; Adams, Joseph Quincy. Committee on Academic Records of the Faculty of the College of Arts and Sciences; Poem by Adams; Clock Tower; Carnegie Foundation.
- AD Miscellaneous., 1923-36 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Adams, Joseph Quincy; Heckscher, August; Wilder, Malcolm L.; Adams, Katherine Rogers. University Apartment Houses.
- AD-AF Miscellaneous., 1923-34 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Adams, Katherine Rogers; Adelmann, Howard B.; Affeld, Frank 0. College of Engineering; Committee on Administrative Engineering; Establishment of the Office of the Director of Admissions.
- AG Miscellaneous., 1931-37 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Warren, George F.; Babcock, Howard E.; Foster, Edward S.; Ladd, Carl E.; Sexauer, Fred H.; Agnew, Arthur L.; Davis, Chester C.; Wallace, Henry A. New York State College of Agriculture deanship.
- AG-AK Miscellaneous., [1917] 1923-36 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  New York State College of Agriculture Alumni Association.
- AL Miscellaneous., 1921-35 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  University of Alabama; Albania.
- AL Miscellaneous., 1924-36 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Alderman, Edwin A.; Seely, Grace; Orth, Professor; Alien, Arthur A.; Ford, Edsel B. University of Virginia.
- AL-ALT Miscellaneous., 1927-34 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Alien, Arthur A.; Arnot, Matthias H.; Altschul, Harold M. Alpha Phi Delta.
- ALU-ALZ Miscellaneous., 1922-35 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Bretz, J. P.; Dean, Arthur H.; Alzugaray, Mario. Alumni Institute; Alumni matters; University of Havana; Cuba.
- American A Miscellaneous., 1922-37 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Eastman, Edward R.; Morgenthau, Henry. American Academy of Political and Social Science; American Agriculturist; American Association for the Advancement of Science.
- American A-B Miscellaneous., 1923-36 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  American Association of University Professors; American Association of University Women; American Bankers Association Foundation; American Birth Control League.
- American C Miscellaneous., 1928-35 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Ward, Harry F. American Chemical Society; American Civil Liberties Union; Academic freedom.
- American Council on Education., 1927-35 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Mann, C. R.; Zook, George F.
- American Council on Education., 1921-27 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Robertson, David A.; Mann, C. R. American University Union in Europe; Academic freedom.
- American Council on Education., 1920-37 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Zook, George F.
- American D-F Miscellaneous., 1930-37 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Huntington, Ellsworth; Lape, Esther Everett. American Eugenics Society; American Farm Bureau Federation; American Foundation Studies in Government.
- American F-I Miscellaneous., 1930-37 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Lape, Esther Everett; Bok, William Curtis; Gallup, George H. The American Foundation; American Hebrew, American Institute of Public Opinion.
- American I-L Miscellaneous., 1924-37 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  American Legislators' Association.
- American L-O Miscellaneous., 1930-36 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Hutton, E. F. American Medical Association; American Olympic Committee.
- American P Miscellaneous., 1924-33 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Lape, Esther Everett. The American Foundation; American Peace Award; American Philological Association.
- American P Miscellaneous., 1925-37 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  American Philological Association; American Philosophical Society.
- American P Miscellaneous., 1934-35 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  American Provident Society; American Psychiatric Association.
- American R-S Miscellaneous., 1923-36 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  American-Russian Chamber of Commerce; American Scandinavian Foundation; American Social Hygiene Association.
- American S-Y Miscellaneous., 1924-37 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  American Society of Mechanical Engineers; American Student Health Association.
- American University Union in Europe., 1923-31 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  American Council on Education.
- American University Union in Europe., 1921-24 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- American - AND Miscellaneous., 1929-34 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Anderson, Charles H.; Anderson, Melville B. Americanism; Amherst College.
- AND Miscellaneous., 1924-34 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Anderson, W. A.; Andrews, E. P.; Andrews, William J. Veterans of Foreign Wars.
- ANE-APP Miscellaneous., 1926-36 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Angell, James R.; de Prorok, Byron; Heyman, Richard. Yale University; Animal experimentation; Antivivisection movement.
- College of Architecture - ARI Miscellaneous., 1930-36 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Young, George. Architectural Advisory Board.
- ARI-ARS Miscellaneous., 1921-35 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Crampton, C. Ward; Peer, Sherman; Aronovici, Carol. Aristogenic Association; Armistice Day; Arnot Forest.
- ART - Associated Miscellaneous., 1930-31 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Ashbery, R. S. Alumni Corporation.
- College of Arts and Sciences Deanship., 1921-28 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Palmer, Archie M. Committee on Educational Policy.
- Association of American Universities., 1928-36 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  Furniss, Edgar S.
- Association of American Universities., 1922-27 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Robertson, David A.; Lloyd, Alfred H. University of North Carolina.
- Associations Miscellaneous - Association of American Medical Colleges., 1926-36 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  Association of American and German Industries; Association of American Colleges; Academic freedom.
- Association of Colleges and Universities of the State of New York., 1927-35 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Ferry, Frederick C.
- Association of Colleges and Preparatory Schools of the Middle States and Maryland - Associations Miscellaneous., 1922-36 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Farrand, Wilson.
- Associations Miscellaneous., 1924-33 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  Association of Community Chests and Councils; Association of Governing Boards of State Universities and Allied Institutions; Association of Urban Universities.
- Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Universities., 1930-35 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- ASTRO-AUS Miscellaneous., 1925-34 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Atkins, Gaius Glenn; Atkinson, Alfred A.; Auden, George A. Meadville Theological School; Unitarian Laymen's League.
- AUS Miscellaneous., 1924-34 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Austen, Willard; Emanuel, Victor. Cornell University Library; Wordsworth Collection.
- AUS-AUT Miscellaneous., 1920-30 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Austen, Willard; Teagle, Walter C. Cornell University Library; University of Tokyo; Committee on Student Ownership of Automobiles.
- AUT-AY Miscellaneous., 1927-29 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  Baker, Newton Diehl.
- Athletics., 1933-35 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  Whinery, Andrew J. Cornell University Athletic Association; Committee of Athletic Control.
- Athletics., 1934-35 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  Cornell University Athletic Association; Syracuse University.
- Athletics., 1935 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Committee Investigating Organization and Procedure in Athletics; Cornell University Athletic Association; Committee on Athletics.
- Athletics., 1935 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Committee of Athletic Control; Cornell University Athletic Association.
- Athletics., 1934-37 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Conant, James Bryant; Dobie, Gilmour; Lynah, James. Committee on Athletics; Cornell University Athletic Association; Carnegie Foundation.
- Athletics., 1935 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Pfann, George R.; Young, Charles V. P.
- Athletics., 1935 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Cornell University Athletic Association.
- Athletics., 1931-35 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Lynah, James; Becker, Carl; Diederichs, Herman. Committee of Athletic Control.
- Babcock Miscellaneous., 1930-37 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Babcock, Howard E.; Hopkins, Harry; Hiscock, Frank H.; Babcock, Stephen M. G. L. F. Cooperative Exchange; New York State Grange.
- BABI-BAIL Miscellaneous., 1924-31 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Babiy, Paul Peter; Bacon, George W.; Bagrationoff, Anatole; Bailey, Frank B.; Bailey, I. W. Anti-semitism; College of Arts and Sciences; Sphinx Head.
- BAIL-BAK Miscellaneous., 1921-37 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Bailey, I. W.; Bailey, Liberty Hyde; Bailey, Ethel Zoe; Baillie, John; Baker, Ernest L. Bailey Hall.
- BAK Miscellaneous., 1922-25 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Baker, George F.; Cornell, Ezra; Miller, Nathan G.
- BAK Miscellaneous., 1930-36 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Baker, George F.; Baker, James B. Volant. Baker Laboratory.
- Baldwin Miscellaneous., 1926-36 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Baldwin, Edward R.
- BALL-BAN Miscellaneous., 1929-37 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Riabouchinsky, Paul; Ballantine, J. Herbert; Ballantine, Percy; Bancroft, Hester. Committee on Broadcasting.
- BAN Miscellaneous., 1928-36 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Bancroft, Wilder D.; McCann, William S.; Nichols, M. L. Heckscher Research Council.
- BAN Miscellaneous., 1919-31 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Bancroft, Wilder D.; Schurman, Jacob Gould; Bangs, John R.
- BAR Miscellaneous., 1926-36 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Barber, S. Morgan; Mann, Albert R.; Barbour, Clarence A.
- BAR Miscellaneous., 1921-37 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Barbour, Clarence A.; Barnes, A. Victor; Barnes, Alfred Smith.
- BARN Miscellaneous., 1922-37 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Barnes, Fred Asa; Barnes, Alfred Smith; Barnum, Jerome D.
- BAR Miscellaneous., 1923-33 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Barredo, Manuel; Benton, Guy Potter; Dobie, Gilmour; Barrus, M. F.; Bartlett, Clarence Drew.
- BART-BAT Miscellaneous., 1922-31 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Bartlett, Murray; Barton, Calvin L.; Barton, Frank A.; Bason, G. F.
- BAT-BOX Miscellaneous., 1926-36 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Bateman, Warner M.; Bates, Erl A.; Bausch, Edward.
- Beacham, J. W., 1930-32 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Military Department; ROTC.
- Beacham, J. W., 1928-31 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Beacham, J. W., 1927-28 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- BEA Miscellaneous., 1923-37 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Beall, Edgar C.
- BEA-BECK Miscellaneous., 1925-33 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Beavan, A. W.
- Becker, Carl., 1922-33 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  Communism.
- Becker, Carl., 1924-27 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  Messenger Foundation; Committee on the Schiff Lectureship.
- Becker Miscellaneous., 1923-37 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Becker, Carl; Becker, Neal Dow.
- BEC-BED Miscellaneous., 1921-31 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  Bedell, Frederick.
- Belgium., 1920-1930 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Sumner, James B.; Galpin, Perrin C.
- BELL-BENE Miscellaneous., 1921-33 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  Collyer, Robert; Bell, Harold I.; Cornell, Mary Emily.
- BEN-BENN Miscellaneous., 1924-37 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  Benner, Thomas E.; Bennett, Charles Edwin; Bennett, Lawrence. University of Puerto Rico; Benjamin Franklin Endowment Fund; Bennington College.
- BENN-BENT Miscellaneous., 1928-35 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  Bentley, John; Bentley, Madison. Bennington College; Dept. of Psychology.
- BENT Miscellaneous., 1922-36 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  Bentley, Madison; Benton, Guy Potter.
- Berry, Romeyn., 1926-29 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  Toboggan slide; Cornell University Athletic Association.
- Berry, Romeyn., 1922-27 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  Poate, Fred W.
- Berry, Romeyn., 1921-23 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  Moore, Fred W. Schoellkopf Field.
- Berry, Romeyn., 1931-36 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  Nathan, George Jean; Brundage, Avery. American Olympic Committee.
- Berry, Romeyn., 1928-35 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  Sampson, Martin W.; Nathan, George Jean; Kirby, Gustavus T.
- Berry, Romeyn., 1927-31 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  Crew.
- BER-BET Miscellaneous., 1922-34 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  Bernays, Edward L.; Bessig, Emma; Berry, Martha; Bethe, Hans.
- Beta Lactose., 1928-29 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  Sharp, Paul F.; Van Cleef, Mynderse. National Milk Sugar Company; Rosemary Creamery Company.
- Betten, Cornelius., 1923-24 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  New York State College of Agriculture.
- Betten, Cornelius., 1921-23 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Betten, Cornelius., 1924-25 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Ladd, Carl E. New York State College of Agriculture; Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial; Potash-Marl Company.
- Betten, Cornelius, 1924-25 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Van Rensselaer, Martha. New York State College of Agriculture.
- Betten, Cornelius., 1925-26 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  White, J. DuPratt. New York State College of Agriculture.
- Betten, Cornelius., 1927-29 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Betten, Cornelius., 1930-31 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Betten, Cornelius., 1931-33 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Hu, Shih. New York State College of Agriculture; Martha Van Rensselaer Hall.
- Betten, Cornelius., 1933-35 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Betten, Cornelius., 1935-37 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Better-BIR Miscellaneous., 1923-34 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Birch, Raymond R. Biosophical Institute.
- BIR-BIS Miscellaneous., 1921-37 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Sanger, Margaret; Bishop, Morris G. Committee on Federal Legislation for Birth Control.
- BIS-BLA Miscellaneous., 1921-34 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Bishop, Morris G.; Black, Hugh. ROTC.
- BLA Miscellaneous., 1924-35 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Black, Hugh; Black, Russell VanNest; Blair, Charles H.
- Blauvelt, George A., 1920-24 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  State Tuition Scholarships in Cornell University.
- BLA-BLO Miscellaneous., 1922-37 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Block, Harry.
- BLO Miscellaneous., 1922-29 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Blood, Charles H.; Blomfield, Reginald; White, Andrew S.
- BLOM-BOE Miscellaneous., 1928-36 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Boas, Franz; Duggan, Professor; Bobo, Stephen N.; Boesche, A. W. Bloomingdale Hospital; National Socialism and education (Nazism); Germany.
- BOE-BOG Miscellaneous., 1924-37 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Boesche, A. W.; Bogert, George G. College of Law.
- BOG Miscellaneous., 1922-32 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Bogert, George G. College of Law; Cornell Cooperative Society.
- BOK-BON Miscellaneous., 1925-36 (Box 3, Folder 19)